You're about to start this data scientists nanodegree program,
你马上就要开始数据科学家纳米学位课程的学习了
but before we get started,
但在学习开始之前
it's probably important to talk a little bit about what do data scientists actually do.
我们很有必要了解一下数据科学家们在工作中具体都在做什么
So, to do that,
那就从我们开始吧
Juno and I both have experience working as data scientists in practice,
Juno 和我都有在行业内从事数据科学家工作的经验
and Juno, can you give the students
Juno 你可以跟我们说说
a little insight into what your role look like as a data scientist?
你在之前的数据科学工作中都负责哪些事情？
Sure. So I was a data scientist at a smaller startup.
当然 我以前在一家小的初创企业担任数据科学家的工作
So, I had a few different roles.
我当时有好几个角色
About 20 percent of my role was more in business analytics,
大概 20% 的时间 我是在做商业分析
and actually I worked a lot with the software development team,
事实上 我跟很多软件开发团队的同事们一起工作
to make sure that before I did any data science,
主要是确保我们拿到的数据都是干净和符合要求的
the data that was being recorded was clean and standardized so that it made sense.
以便进一步的分析
I gave things like activity reports on
我会用数据做一些用户行为的报告
what kind of users and products were happening at the time.
比如说 哪些用户目前使用哪些产品
About 80 percent of my role was on longer-term data science projects,
80% 的工作是做一些长期大型的数据科学项目
where I worked on a recommender system,
比如说 我做过一个推荐系统
that recommended different products to users,
它可以把不同的产品推荐给我们的用户
and also just making sense of the information we have in our database,
或者只是更好地理解我们数据库里面的信息
such as clusters of similar products we had,
比如说 哪些产品之间是相似的
or insights for our users.
如何更好地去理解用户
I heard your role as a data scientist was a bit different,
我听说你的工作内容跟我的有点不一样
could you share a little bit about that?
你能跟我们说一说吗
Yes. So, I was a data scientist at a larger company,
当然 我当时是在一个比较大的公司从事数据科学这份工作
and the communication and your role sounds like it was mostly with software developers.
你当时是跟很多软件工程师们一起工作
Yeah.
是的
Mine was very customer facing,
我的工作更多的是是面向客户
and so that meant,
也就是说
most of the time my audience was a less technical audience,
我的听众大多数是一些缺乏技术背景的人
and it was important for me to make sure that they
所以 对我来说 把我做的工作清晰地
understood what they were going to get from what we were working on,
从一个商业的角度呈现给他们
from a business perspective.
是很重要的
The tools that we were using were probably very similar.
我们用的工具估计比较类似
I used things related to natural language processing and clustering,
我用过很多跟自然语言处理还有聚类相关的
used sort of a Python toolkit,
Python 软件工具包
something that students will be learning in this program.
很多内容 我们的同学在本次课程中也会学到
From there, it's probably important that we give more insight than just ours.
接下来 我们再来跟其他数据科学家们聊一聊
So, you'll hear from some of our partners,
他们大多在我们的各大合作伙伴公司里工作
and they'll give you some insight into what they do as data scientists
他们会告诉我们 他们在自己工作中的职责
as well as what they look for in candidates when they're hiring data scientists.
以及他们在招聘数据科学家的时候 会看重哪些特质